# WILLIAMS ISAAC OLADELE

5a, Ajegunle Street, Off Harry Man Block, Ota (234) 8146877423, williamscalg@gmail.com

### **Summary:**

Developer of CogentPHP ADS, energetic and imaginative young software developer who is able to work alongside other talented IT professionals in developing softwares to the very highest standards. Williams has a high awareness of industry issues and trends, particularly in regard to accessibility, usability, emerging technologies, and open source CMS. He has the drive and massive energy needed to really make a difference to a project.

Extensive experience in developing web applications using PHP, HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Content Management Systems with emphasis on semantic HTML, W3C and usability standards.

Develop responsive websites and cross-browser testing across various devices desktop, mobile and tablets.

Profiles: https://github.com/wilforlan

https://app.plum.io/profile/5c0bc49ca385ef6e32662eddf3abc5a0b1503da3

https://facebook.com/wilforlan

Framework Location https://github.com/wilforlan/CogentPHP

## **Personal Information**

Date of Birth: August 4, 1993

L.G.A: Ado- Odo Ota LGA

Next Of Kin: Williams Esther

# Skills / Tools

Languages: PHP, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, , Bootstrap, PHP.

**Tools/Utilities:** Text Mate, Atom, Sublime, PHPStorm, GIT.

Web Server: Apache Web Server, Internet Information Server (IIS). RDBMS/DBMS: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server 6.5, Microsoft Access.

**Operating System:** Mac OS X, Windows 8,7/XP.

# **Frameworks**

PHP: CogentPHP

Laravel Codelgniter

CSS: Twitter Bootstrap

Semantic UI Foundation

JavaScript: JQuery

VueJs AngularJS

# Cultural Awareness

Proficiency at understanding the perspective of others, and dealing effectively with different types of people.

Disposition for being curious, reflective and studying people and their values.

Disposition for adapting to a wide range of people, and being open to differences in attitudes, values and personalities.

Strong ability to be encouraging, sensitive, and make others feel comfortable and appreciated.

Communicate in a tactful and considerate manner in difficult situations, and help others settle interpersonal conflicts.

# **Decision Making**

Proficiency for making high-quality decisions based on limited information.

Ability for being thorough, deliberate and timely, and having attention to detail.

Disposition for gathering and critically evaluating relevant information, recognizing solutions and using facts, logic and experience to buttress your opinions.

Ability for expressing your opinions and beliefs and a tendency for exerting dominance.

# Innovation

Proficiency at generating creative ideas, out-of-the-box solutions to problems.

Disposition for working with abstract ideas and developing unconventional solutions.

Disposition for being receptive and flexible to different ideas, perspectives, and changing demands.

Understand the basic problems at work and generate possible solutions.

# Task Management

Proficiency for setting goals, monitoring progress, and taking initiative to improve your work.

Can work independently, establish and meet challenging deadlines, persevere even when initially unsuccessful, and not settle for "good enough."

Have the ability for maintaining accuracy and attention to detail, reporting and recordkeeping, setting goals and creating plans to accomplish the work, as well as monitoring and controlling resources.

Can remain calm, level-headed and operate effectively in the midst of stressful situations and under multiple or conflicting demands.

Ability to learn what is important to get the job done right and avoid mistakes. You are also able to understand new procedures and explain them to others.

## **Software Development**

- Developing PSR-0 and PSR-4 Compliant softwares
- Adhering to coding standard by following standard programming procedures
- Knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms
- Proper use of dependency manager both in PHP and NodeJs
- Developing highly scalable applications that works both on web and mobile
- Experience in developing PHP Based Web Application in MVC.
- Experience in developing MVC Framework in PHP
- Extensive knowledge of using git both for version and local development within team

#### General

- Account handling, supervising, mentoring and presentation skills.
- Experienced in development under OSX / Windows and UNIX environments. Not afraid of the command line.
- Use of GIT for Version Control.
- Fluent English both Oral and Writing.
- Playing the role of team leads not only of developers, but also entrepreneurs.

#### Other relevant experience

- Branding (Logo Design, Writing, Advertisement, Marketing).
- Proper and Good use of Graphics Design Software (Corel Draw).
- Extensive knowledge of User Interface and User Experience Designs

# **WORK HISTORY**

#### SENIOR SOFWARE DEVELOPER

# CRYSTAL HILLS SOFTWARES May, 2016 to August, 2016

Crystal Hills Softwares, with professional knowledge in developing highly scalable softwares with modern design patterns, Crystal Hills Softwares delivers high quality sofwares to clients across the nation.

Environment: Apache, MySQL, PHP7.0/5.5, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Eclipse.

# Responsibilities:

- Developed Payroll Management Software that interfaces with Time Tracking Devices
- Developed API Oriented Applications and Libraries to easy development Process

- Developed School Management Software to ease Account and Academics Tracking Process for Schools
- Programmed high ranking Point Of Sales Applications that works well with modern POS Printers and Barcode Scanners
- Oversaw Software Website Development Project and Kept records together with phase tracking
- Developed Account Management Software used for Record Keeping and Balancing
- Interfacing Hardwares that work perfectly with web applications
- Trained IT Students on Developing Softwares with high profiles
- Code maintenance and proper documentation of softwares
- Interfacing with clients in other to understand Client's point of view so as to deliver high quality programs

# **Lead Web Developer / Instructor**

#### **Prime Grace Computer Institute**

February 2015 - July 2015

Environment: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, Fireworks, Apache Web Server

#### Responsibilities:

- Create responsive website and corporate designs.
- Contributed user interface design mockups and designs.
- Trained and mentored students through design process and coding standards.
- Worked with product groups to develop and enhance usability.
- Led front-end projects to a timely and successful completion.
- Develop semantic and valid XHTML/CSS templates in agile environment where wire frames and visual design were simultaneously being produced.
- Used JQuery for creating JavaScript behaviors.
- Played multiple roles as Build Developer and Defects Developer.
- Provided Report Document after the completion of development.

# Web Developer / Intern

#### **Hibee Tech Consult**

January 2013 to June 2013

With over 50 website and content management projects completed to date, Hibee Tech Consult has the experience to guide an organization with both online and back-office initiatives. They are experts in user-experience and social media planning to records management and workflow process definition.

Environment: HTML5, XHTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Eclipse.

# Responsibilities:

- Developed HTML/CSS based website for co-intern students.
- Worked on html/css development for the organization. And created Mobile website which would render in IOS, Droid and Blackberry Environments
- Use of wordpress and joomla for web design
- Worked in Agile environment, attending daily scrum meetings.
- Attend wire frame review, design and html code walkthrough meetings.

#### Other Experience:

# Shadowbloggers.

An online blogging website dedicated to providing real time events updates.

#### Responsibilities:

- Development and management of website through daily updates.
- · Covered events on different occasions.
- Write web contents based on event attendance.
- Documentation of user statistics.
- Management of social media network.

# Upwork Freelance Web Developer.

Work as a freelance web developer for different clients.

# Responsibilities:

- Performed graphical design and web site contract work for small businesses and working professionals.
- Handled duties ranging from creative design to code implementation.
- Documentations.

# **Educational History**

**Coker Area Comprehensive High School** 

2011

The Polytechnic, Ibadan (In-View)

2012 - 2016

# **Contribution / Awards**

Outstanding Personality in Education, Ogun State, Year 2012

Outstanding Portfolio (Web Development Category), Behance Portfolio Reviews, Year 2015

Winner, Shadow Developers Development Competiton, Year 2012

Contribution in stack overflow forums.

# **Hobbies / Interest**

- Programming
- Playing Chess
- Reading
- Swimming and recreation

## References

Available on request.